<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.7.4">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2019-05-24T15:34:26+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Sam’s Notes</title><subtitle>This site is currently being built. It will be both a collection of useful information and an online portfolio of some of my projects</subtitle><author><name>Samuel Sheehy</name></author><entry><title type="html">Let the Blog Begin!</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/meta/2019/05/20/let-the-blog-begin.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Let the Blog Begin!" /><published>2019-05-20T18:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2019-05-20T18:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/meta/2019/05/20/let-the-blog-begin</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/meta/2019/05/20/let-the-blog-begin.html">&lt;p&gt;Hello! This is my first offical blog post. There have been lots
of different projects I’ve been meaning to persue for a while.
This little blog is going to be a way for me to record the different
projects I complete over time. I also want to create little collections
of learning ressources for various topics.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In fact, my first post is going to be a collection of links and other
ressources for learning Git!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The layout of this blog will surely progress over time. At the moment
I’m not very happy with the layout, but I do not know enough about Jekyll
to change it too much - though to be honest, I still don’t know 
exactly what I want either in this regard…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Time to get to work!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Samuel Sheehy</name></author><summary type="html">Hello! This is my first offical blog post. There have been lots of different projects I’ve been meaning to persue for a while. This little blog is going to be a way for me to record the different projects I complete over time. I also want to create little collections of learning ressources for various topics.</summary></entry></feed>